{
    "id": "90943c28680a451c97a01bad2dbb1548",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Worksheet",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He stole the bike ……………………….. belonged to his neighbor.",
            "description": "Which is used to refer to things. That can also refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have no money …………………….. I can lend you.",
            "description": "That can refer to both people and things. It is more common than which after words like no, all, any etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The dog ……………………….. I adopted from a shelter is my best friend now.",
            "description": "Which is used to refer to things. That can also refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He lives in the same house ………………………….. he was born.",
            "description": "Where can mean in which.",
            "answers": [
                "where",
                "which",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Those ………………………… are content do not need any wealth.",
            "description": "Who refers to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We met a girl …………………………… was carrying a flower basket on her head.",
            "description": "Who refers to people. It acts as the subject of the relative clause.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The horse ………………………….. I bought the other day is lame.",
            "description": "Which is used to refer to things. That can also refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t trust people …………………………. go back on their promises.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I talked to the young girl ………………………… looked worried.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "she",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I lost the watch ………………………… I bought last week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The castle …………………………. stands on that hill was built in the 16th century.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "A man ………………………… is loyal will have many friends.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses both who and that can refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}